Guide to the McMurry Richey papers, 1935-1985 UA.29.02.0227
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Continuing Education, 1960-1985; 2
  - Alumni Association, Convocation, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education Plans, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education Expenses, 1971-1973 (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education Expenses, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Expense Accounts, 1974-1978 (Box 8)
  - Lay-Clergy Conference, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
  - Spring Institute for Ministry, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Women's Interseminary Conference and Women in Church and Ministry, 1974 January-June (Box 8)
  - Individual Continuing Education Project, 1977-1979 (Box 8)
  - DeArmon Hunter: Study Program, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - District Seminars, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Convocation, 1979 July-October (Box 8)
  - Alumni Council, Reunion Plans, 1976-1979 (Box 8)
  - Benjamin N. Duke, Parish Ministry Fund Fellowships, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education Plans, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
  - SACEM and APEM, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - S.E. Jurisdictional Association of Conference Boards of Ministry, Atlanta, 1977 November-December (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education Services: Durham Ministerial Association, 1972-1976 (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education: The Durham Area, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Inquiries (and Replies) Regarding Continuing Education, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education Plans, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Lay-Clergy Dialogue, 1975 February-May (Box 8)
  - Parish/Staff Type Ministries, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education Materials: Lecture Programs, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - "Liturgy and Education": Seminar and Retreat, 1977 June (Box 8)
  - Continuing Education: Plans, Schedules, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
  - Educational Affairs Council, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
- Curriculum Committee, 1959-1971; 3
  - Curriculum Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Divinity School: Needs, Plans, 1959 January (Box 9)
  - Seniors and Other Students Response to Curriculum Committee, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Revision, Miscellaneous Materials, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1969 April-May (Box 9)
  - New Curriculum, 1969 January-February (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Revision, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Revision, 1969 January-April (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1969 January-February (Box 9)
  - Reading Courses, Independent Study, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Degree and Curriculum Revision Ad Hoc Committee, 1966 (Box 9)
- Junior Seminars, 1965-1969; 4
  - Junior Colloquia, 1965-1969 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminars: Syllabi for all Sections, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Plans for Junior Seminars, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminars: Section IV, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminar 9: Section VI, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminar: Plans, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminar VII, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminar IX, 1965-1968 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminars: Plans, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Junior Seminars: Section VII, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
- Reports, Research, and Correspondence, 1955-1983; 5
  - Divinity School Plans: New Faculty, Prospects, 1983 February-May (Box 9)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1983 August (Box 9)
  - Report of Self-Study, 1983 December (Box 9)
  - Divinity School Self Study Reports, 1982-1984 (Box 9)
  - The Church and the Minister's Vocation, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
  - Ministerial Training, 1955-1957 (Box 9)
  - The Church and the Minister's Vocation, 1955-1961 (Box 9)
  - The Ministry, 1957-1962 (Box 9)
  - Bibliographies and Guides, P.S. 10, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Church and Ministry Course, Undated (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Faculty Reports, Papers, 1970-1979 (Box 10)
  - Black Studies Program and 1978 Concerns, 1972-1978 (Box 10)
  - Dean Jameson Jones, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Write: Acting Deanship, 1976-1978 (Box 10)
  - P.S. 10 Church and Ministry, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence to File, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1974 August-December (Box 10)
  - Divinity School Seminars: Columbia and Richmond, "The Role of the Christian Minister Today", 1970 May-November (Box 10)
  - World Council of Churches, 1961 (Box 10)
  - World Council of Churches: New Delhi Conference, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - "Concerned Clergymen", 1967 December (Box 10)
  - Belief, Undated (Box 10)
  - Thomas R. Sigmon, "A Church and the Effects of Racial Change", 1973 May (Box 10)
  - Richard Bower, "The Church and the Urban Future", 1980 (Box 10)
  - Christian Theology 325: Ted R. Morton, 1955-1956 (Box 10)
  - Continuing Education Seminar: Ellison and Richey, 1969 (Box 10)
  - The Christian Student Movement in Korea, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Williams, "Self-Presence as Acknowledgement and Indwelling of Immediacy", 1971 May (Box 10)
  - The Young Wesley's Concept of Devotion: A Confluence of Traditions, 1973 April (Box 10)
  - Dulaney, Theology of Reinhold Niebuhr, 1974 January (Box 10)
  - J. Harley Cecil, "The Philosophy of Reul L. Howe", 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Ronald A Koont's Paper, 1973-1976 (Box 10)
  - Toward a Lay Training Program and Center in Malaysia and Singapore, 1971 June (Box 10)
  - Philip Emerson, Honors Thesis, "Four Radical Theologians? Anthropology, Death of God Movement", 1972 May (Box 10)
  - Center for Parish Development: Center Letter, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - World Methodist Council Mission Consultation, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Institute for Advanced Pastoral Studies, 1959-1965 (Box 10)
  - Alumni Visits: SC, VA Conferences, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Higher Education and Ministry: UMC and other Higher Education Materials, 1974-1976 (Box 10)
  - Bishop's Conference: United Methodist Education in North Carolina, 1972 May-July (Box 10)
  - Directors of Christian Education and Church School Superintendents' Conference, Lake Junaluska, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Report to Board of Visitors, 1959-1964 (Box 10)
  - Duke Divinity School, 1964-1967 (Box 10)
  - Alumni Committee and Related Matters, 1958-1963 (Box 10)
  - Annual Conference Visitations: Virginia, WNC, 1958-1965 (Box 10)
  - Duke University Religions Council name change to Duke University Christian Council, 1969 (Box 10)
  - DURC: Current, 1966-1968 (Box 10)
  - DURC, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - Ecumenical Campus Ministry: Duke University Christian Movement, UCM, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
  - DURC: UCM Action, 1966-1968 (Box 11)
  - Dai-Gong: Peace is the Way, 1975 May (Box 11)
  - Publications and Calendars, 1979-1981 (Box 11)
  - Divinity School Committee on Lectures and Public Events (File from Thor Hall), 1970-1972 (Box 11)
  - Lecture Program Committee, 1968-1972 (Box 11)
  - Lecture Program Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 11)
  - Lecture Program Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - Lecture Program Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 11)
  - Documents Relative to Divinity School Governance, 1965-1977 (Box 11)
  - James A. Gray Lectureship, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Frank S. Hickman Lectureship, 1978 August (Box 11)
  - Lecture Program Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
- Early Course Materials, Student Work, 1935-1977; 6
  - Sort, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
  - Mass Outlaws, 1955-1972 (Box 11)
  - "Study of Theological Education" and Other Materials on Preparation for the Ministry, 1949-1961 (Box 11)
  - Stevenson, "Rethinking the Pastoral Ministry", 1950 (Box 11)
  - Kale, "Reports on Practical Studies"; Anderson, "Theological Education in America", 1951-1959 (Box 11)
  - Durham Study Commission Report, "Racial Separation and Class Stratification in the Local Church", Undated (Box 11)
  - Division of Christian Education, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - "Myths, Stories, History, Eschatology, and Action;" The New Republic, "Parish Clinical Training;" "The Fall of Infallibility;" "The Origins of Religion in a Child", 1967-1968 (Box 11)
  - "A Faith to Teach By", 1959-1960 (Box 11)
  - Mayhew Materials, Undated (Box 11)
  - Integration Petition, Divinity School, 1956-1961 (Box 11)
  - Bible Study, 1935-1937 (Box 11)
  - Early Course Materials, Term Papers, 1935-1940 (Box 11)
  - College Course Notes, 1935 February-May (Box 11)
  - The Genetic Psychology of Religion Coursebook, Undated (Box 11)
  - The Christian Century [Four Issues], 1956-1961 (Box 11)
  - The Work of the Minister, 1959 (Box 11)
  - The Theology of Pastoral Care, 1966-1969 (Box 11)
  - Senior Seminar 66: The Christian Church and Social Change, 1956-1958 (Box 11)
  - P.C. 188, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Vocational Group IV Qualifying: The Theology of Pastoral Care, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
  - Seminar 70: Pastoral Care and Preaching, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Vocational Group IV Qualifying Final, 1962-1966 (Box 11)
  - Seminar for Pastoral Care Majors, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Training Course 130b: Christian Education in the Church, 1950-1955 (Box 11)
  - Training Courses: Leader's Guides, Certificates, Manual, 1954-1956 (Box 12)
  - Motive Article, Prophetic Religion Article, 1939-1948 (Box 12)
  - Reading Reports on "Christianity and the Philosophy of History", 1950 August (Box 12)
  - Current American Theology, 1952 January (Box 12)
  - Periodical Articles: "Why Ministers Break Down", 1956-1959 (Box 12)
  - My Published Articles, 1960-1964 (Box 12)
  - Sermons, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
  - MSS for the Pulpit: Sermon and Review, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
  - Sabbatical Leave: Plans, Report, 1960-1963 (Box 12)
  - My Book Reviews, 1955-1962 (Box 12)
  - Reviews, 1961 (Box 12)
  - News Articles, Theological, 1969-1971 (Box 12)
  - Christian Ethics and Contemporary Culture, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Institute for Advanced Pastoral Studies, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - The Ministry, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
  - The Ministry, Report, Alumni Correspondence, 1973 (Box 12)
  - "The Ministerial Image", 1965 (Box 12)
  - Reports, Master of Theology Program, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
  - The Ministry, 1957-1965 (Box 12)
  - Christian Ethics, 1948 (Box 12)
  - Letters, Answered or Initiated, 1962 (Box 12)
  - Clippings, 1955-1957 (Box 12)
  - Sit-In Demonstrations, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Sit-Ins and Trials, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Kirkridge Retreat, 1948-1957 (Box 12)
  - Faculty Christian Fellowship: Publications, 1954-1956 (Box 12)
  - Psychology of Religion, 1936-1952 (Box 12)
  - Religion and the Good Society, edited by Benson Y. Landis, 1943 (Box 12)
  - Pamphlets, 1958-1976 (Box 12)
  - Pamphlets, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Term Papers, 1935-1951 (Box 12)
  - Christian Ethic and War, 1938-1949 (Box 12)
  - Christian Ethics, Undated (Box 12)
  - Christian Ethics Pamphlets, 1952-1976 (Box 12)
  - Ethics and Social Programs Pamphlets, 1956-1960 (Box 12)
  - Publications, 1956-1972 (Box 12)
  - Black Experience and Theology, 1970-1977 (Box 12)
  - Evanston Materials, 1954 (Box 12)
  - Reappraisal of the Ministry, 1962 (Box 12)
  - The Task of the Minister Today: "Servant of Whose Word?", 1959 (Box 12)
  - Committee Reports, Publications, 1953-1958 (Box 12)
  - Evangelism and the Church School, 1956-1959 (Box 13)
  - Facts Forum, 1952-1953 (Box 13)
  - Training Course: Interpreting the Bible to Youth, 1947 (Box 13)
  - Clippings from "Christian Friends Bulletin", 1947 (Box 13)
  - Committee Minutes, Reports; Book List, Founder's Day Program, 1956-1958 (Box 13)
  - Seminar 68: Christian Experience and Contemporary Life, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Seminar 67: The New Testament as Materials for Teaching, 1955-1957 (Box 13)
  - Rightest Extremism, 1960-1971 (Box 13)
  - Packet on the Churches and Extremists, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Book Notes, circa 1940s (Box 13)
  - Criticisms of Culture: American Social Economic Life, 1954-1957 (Box 13)
  - Thesis Announcement, 1954 April (Box 13)
  - Segregation and Integration, 1955-1958 (Box 13)
  - Race Relations Seminar, 1937-1955 (Box 13)
  - New Testament Papers, 1949 (Box 13)
  - New Testament Studies: The Gospels, Undated (Box 13)
  - Stories [Sermon Preparation], Undated (Box 13)
  - Bible Studies: Galatians, Undated (Box 13)
  - Philosophy of Christian Education, 1952-1953 (Box 13)
  - Memorial Service, 1956-1960 (Box 13)
  - Memorials and Mementos: Old Friends, W.A. Stanbury, 1954-1957 (Box 13)
  - Notes for Sermons, circa 1951 (Box 13)
  - Plans for Fall Talks, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Talks, 1946-1951 (Box 13)
  - For Student Talks and Youth Programs, 1946-1948 (Box 13)
  - Plans for Talks and Sermons, 1953 (Box 13)
  - Cullowhee: Religious Emphasis Week [Atomic Energy], 1946-1947 (Box 13)
  - Training Course: "How the Bible Came to Be", 1937-1943 (Box 13)
  - Riverside: Youth Activities Week Talks, 1948-1951 (Box 13)
  - Urbana Worship Service, Undated (Box 13)
  - Clippings, 1951-1965 (Box 13)
- Ethics, 1945-1959; 7
  - Naturalism or Evolutionary Ethics, Undated (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Contemporary Morality and Other Inadequate Standards, Undated (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Hedonism and Utilitarianism, Undated (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Absolutism and Relativism, 1950 (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Study Guides, Tests, Undated (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Ethical Theories, Intuitional Theories, Undated (Box 13)
  - Introduction to Ethics: Defined and Differentiated from Other Sciences, Choice, Values, etc., 1948 (Box 13)
  - Economic Ethics, Undated (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Self-Realization, Undated (Box 13)
  - Formalism: Definitions, Stoicism and Other Formalisms, Undated (Box 13)
  - Clippings, 1946-1951 (Box 13)
  - "Reactionary" Articles, 1948-1951 (Box 13)
  - Pendle Hill Materials, 1949-1954 (Box 13)
  - C.D. Broad, "Egoism as a Theory of Human Motives", 1949 (Box 13)
  - Church and State in Education, 1948 (Box 13)
  - Christianity and Our Civilization, Toynbee et al., 1947-1948 (Box 13)
  - Religion in the Public Schools of North Carolina, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Ethics and Religious Belief, Undated (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Traditional Schools Summarized, Undated (Box 13)
  - Ethics: Methods of Study, Undated (Box 13)
  - Old Testament Survey, 1945 (Box 13)
  - Nashville Seminar: Community, 1945-1947 (Box 13)
  - Christian Social Ethics: Materials from Course, 1947-1948 (Box 13)
  - Notes from Duke Seminar: "Christian Bases of Political Action", 1947-1949 (Box 13)
  - Pamphlets, 1966-1975 (Box 13)
- Laity and Related Topics, 1948-1976; 8
  - Laity and Business Ethics, 1961-1968 (Box 13)
  - Conference Proceedings and Journals, 1959-1974 (Box 13)
  - Pamphlets, Conference Proceedings, Journals, 1967-1976 (Box 13)
  - East Harlem Protestant Parish; Pamphlets, Lectionaries, 1960-1964 (Box 13)
  - Lay Renewal and the Columbus Group: Various Lay Centers and Movements, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Theology and the Lay Mind: Old Outlines, Reports, etc., 1957-1959 (Box 14)
  - On the Job Ethics, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - Renewal of the Church: Catholic Hour Series "Renewal", 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - The Missionary Structure of the Congregation: World Council of Churches Study, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Lay Center and Renewal: Christian Faith and Life Community, 1952-1962 (Box 14)
  - Industrial Mission, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Laity: F. H. Littell, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - Laity: Syllabus, Articles; F.H. Littell, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - Church and Industry Institute, 1966-1970 (Box 14)
  - Laity-Clergy Relations, 1966-1970 (Box 14)
  - Lay School of Theology, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - Theology and the Laity: Noteworthy Local Church Programs of Teaching and Renewal, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Lay Centers (Also Church and Industry): Detroit Industrial Mission, 1961-1967 (Box 14)
  - Parishfield, 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Forms of Church Renewal, 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Inter-met, 1972-1979 (Box 14)
  - Theological Publications, 1967-1971 (Box 14)
  - Lay Renewal: Dr. John L. Casteels' Biographies, Lectures, Other Materials, 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Betty Coulbourn, "A Case Study: Interracial Mission as a Locus of Religious Learning in an Urban Parish", 1971 (Box 14)
  - National Parks Ministry, Overseas Study and Service, 1950 (Box 14)
  - Groups, 1958-1960 (Box 14)
  - Layman's Theological Library, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
  - Laity, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
  - Inner City Ministries, 1965-1968 (Box 14)
  - Church and Industry: Presbyterian Institute of Industrial Relations, 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Christian Vocation, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Lay Adult Bible Study, 1949-1959 (Box 14)
  - Theology and the Lay Mind: Current Bibliographies and Course Guides, 1959-1961 (Box 14)
  - Theology and the Laity, 1962-1965 (Box 14)
  - Theology and the Lay Mind: Communication, Language, Problems and Possibilities, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Theology and the Lay Mind: Articles and Materials, 1948-1960 (Box 14)
  - The Doctrine of Man, 1961 June (Box 14)
  - Theology and the Lay Mind: The Church, 1960-1963 (Box 14)
- Church and Society Programs, 1946-1975; 9
  - Time Magazine: Religion, 1954 (Box 14)
  - Time: The Servant Church, 1964 (Box 14)
  - The Ecumenical Institute (Chicago), 1966 March (Box 14)
  - Kirkridge Retreat, 1950-1964 (Box 14)
  - Report and Discussion Papers, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Engineering Education Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Seminar (Nashville): Economic Order, 1947 (Box 14)
  - Federal Council on Church and Economic Life: Detroit Conference, 1950 (Box 14)
  - Federal Council Studies and the Pittsburgh Conference: "Christianity and the Economic Order", 1946-1948 (Box 14)
  - Stanley High, John T. Flynn, and Replies, 1949-1950 (Box 14)
  - Publications on Race in America, 1967-1968 (Box 14)
  - Publications on Poverty, 1966 (Box 15)
  - Operation Breakthrough: Annual Report, 1966 November (Box 15)
  - Poverty Programs, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
  - Poverty Programs, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
  - The United Church Letter (Raleigh): Collins Kilburn, Pastor, 1966-1969 (Box 15)
  - Student Interracial Ministry, 1962-1967 (Box 15)
  - Business Ethics and Religious Ethics, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Experimental Study of Religion and Society, 1964-1973 (Box 15)
  - Experimental Study of Science, Technology, Society and Religion, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Interseminary Church and Society Program, 1968-1969 (Box 15)
  - Interseminary Church and Society Program, 1966-1970 (Box 15)
  - Science and Theology, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
  - Ethics and State Politics, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Ethics and Business Practices, 1966-1967 (Box 15)
  - Ethics and Decision-Making in Industry: Related Materials, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Christian Ethics and Industry, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Symposium: Christian Ethics and Business Ethics, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Ethics and Decision-Making in Industry, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
  - Business and Ethics, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Ethics and Decision-Making in Industry, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
  - Ethics and Decision-Making in Industry: Related Materials, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
  - Triangle Church Renewal Studies, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Research Triangle: Regional Planning Commission, 1964-1967 (Box 15)
  - Continuing Education, 1962-1979 (Box 15)
  - Continuing Education, 1972-1975 (Box 15)
  - Conference Proceedings, 1967-1974 (Box 15)